YMCA ARMED SERVICES DEPARTMENT:
University of Minnesota Libraries
- Prisoner of War Department, minutes, 1915-1918.; 1 volume. (Box 130)
- Prisoner of war work in Germany, E. O. Jacob report, 1917. (Box 130)
- Committee on Work for Allied Armies and Prisoners of War, statement of receipts and expenditures, 1920. (Box 130)
- Miscellaneous newspapers, 1917-1918. (Box 130)
- Miscellaneous reports to Parliament, 1915-1917.; 3 folders. (Box 131)
- Letters from E. C. Carter to William Sloane, originals, 1918-1920.; 3 folders. (Box 131)
- Dots and Dashes, originals, 1917-1919.; 3 folders. (Box 131)
- U.S. Government publications on World War I, 1920.; 2 folders. (Box 131)
- Finance Department, weekly bulletin, 1920. (Box 131)
- Articles on religious aspect of war, 1914. (Box 131)
- Red Triangle Overseas, 1918-1919.; 2 volumes and 5 folders. (Box 132)
- American Home News, 1919. (Box 132)
- Wadsworth Gas Attack, 1917-1918.; 2 folders. (Box 132)
- Religious work pamphlets, 1917-1918.; 22 folders. (Box 133)
- Religious work pamphlets, 1917-1918.; 23 folders. (Box 134)
- Religious work pamphlets, 1917-1918.; 16 folders. (Box 135)
- YMCA answer to the Inspector General, 1918-1920.; 4 volumes. (Box 136)
- Miscellaneous clippings, 1918. (Box 136)
- New York Division Gas Attack, 1918.; 2 folders. (Box 137)
- Border Work, 1917.; 1 volume and 2 folders. (Box 137)
- Reveille, 1919. (Box 137)
- YMCA to Inspector General, 1918-1920.; 3 volumes. (Box 138)
- Evangeliscsher Hausfreund, prisoner of war newspaper, 1916. (Box 139)
- Trench and Camp (originals), 1918. (Box 139)
- Comrades in Service, 1919. (Box 139)
- The Spiker, 1918. (Box 139)
- Camp de Souge News, 1918-1919. (Box 139)
- The British Prisoner of War, 1918.; 2 folders. (Box 139)
- Hot Shot, 1919. (Box 139)
- The Upgrade, 1919. (Box 139)
- Der Gefangenengebote: Monatsschrift fur Kriegsgefangene, 1917-1918. (Box 139)
- Le Messager du Prisonnier de Guerre, 1917-1918. (Box 139)
- The Last Leaf, 1919. (Box 139)
- The Soldiers' Newsletter, 1918.; 2 folders. (Box 139)
- Camp Dix Pictorial Review, 1918. (Box 139)
- Le Cafard Musele, 1917-1918.; 3 folders. (Box 139)
- Welcome, 1918. (Box 139)
- The Flypaper, 1918. (Box 139)
- The Cro, 1918. (Box 139)
- Chicago Tribune, Paris edition (originals), 1919.; 2 folders. (Box 140)
- New York Herald (originals), 1919.; 4 folders. (Box 140)
- Stars and Stripes (originals), 1919.; 2 folders. (Box 140)
- Articles regarding YMCA in World War I, 1918-1919.; 3 folders. (Box 140)
- Chinese Bible, 1918. (Box 140)
- The Y.O.U. Herald, Y Overseas Union, 1924-1925. (Box 140)
- The Rangefinder, Fort Terry, NY, 1916. (Box 140)
- Dots and Dashes, Camp Alfred Vail, NJ (originals), 1918. (Box 140)
- AEF-YMCA in the United Kingdom, R. L. Ewing material, 1919.; 3 folders. (Box 140)
- Report to the Commander in Chief of the YMCA with the AEF, 1919.; 2 folders. (Box 140)
- Post-war investigation of the YMCA, F. S. Edmonds materials, 1917-1939. (Box 140)
- Samples of War Work pamphlets defending YMCA work, 1917-1919. (Box 140)
- Letter from E. C. Carter to William Sloane, supplementing the YMCA answer to the Inspector General, 1918-1920. (Box 140)
- Leave area publications, 1919. (Box 140)
- Miscellaneous U.S. camp announcements, 1918.; 2 folders. (Box 140)
- Die Morgenrote, undated. (Box 140)
- Answers to criticism, circa 1919. (Box 140)
- YMCA-AFG, blueprints for buildings, undated. (Box 140)
- Army and Navy Athletic Handbook, 1919. (Box 140)
- Foyers du Soldat, program, 1918. (Box 140)
- AFG materials, P. Anderson collection, 1919-1925.; 6 folders. (Box 140)
- AMAROC News, 1921. (Box 140)
- Italian army materials, 1918-1919. (Box 140)
- AFG entertainment scrapbook, Koblenz, 1921.; 2 folders. (Box 140)
- No Tobacco Journal, 1918. (Box 140)
- Inter-Allied Games, Regulations Governing the Competitions, 1919. (Box 140)
- United War Work Campaign, China, 1918-1919. (Box 140)
- Athletic Bulletin, unbound duplicates, 1920-1922.; 3 folders. (Box 140)
- AEF-YMCA publication, The Eagle Hut, undated. (Box 140)
- United War Work Campaign, organizational charts, undated. (Box 140)
- Education Commission, The American in France, undated. (Box 140)
- Educational Activities for War Prisoners, undated. (Box 140)
- Prisoner of war report, United Kingdom, undated. (Box 140)
- Prisoner of War material, Italy, 1918-1919. (Box 140)
- Monte Carlo YMCA scrapbook, undated. (Box 140)
- Final report of the Leave Area Department YMCA-AEF, originals, 1919.; 8 folders. (Box 140)
- Leave Area publications, undated. (Box 140)
- Education Commission, cardboard model French coins, undated. (Box 140)
- Handbook of American YMCA-AEF, 1918. (Box 140)
- Various committee meeting minutes, 1918-1921. (Box 140)
- Leave Area publication, plan of Nantes, France, undated. (Box 141)
- AMAROC News, 1920-1921. (Box 141)
- War Work Council, organizational chart, 1918. (Box 141)
- AEF-YMCA in the United Kingdom, building blueprints, 1918. (Box 141)
- AEF-YMCA in the United Kingdom, blank forms, undated (Box 141)
- Mexican border work, circuit maps, undated. (Box 141)
- New York Herald, European edition, American Legion section, 1927. (Box 141)
- AFG materials, P. Anderson collection, undated. (Box 141)
- Record book of conferences of the Women's section of the overseas workers of the YMCA, 1918. (Box 141)
RELATED MATERIALS
Posters relating to the United War Work Campaign can be found the Kautz Family YMCA Archives poster collection.
Additional copies of newspapers (Trench and Camp and others) are separately cataloged in the Kautz Family YMCA Archives serials collection.
An extensive series of World War I-era photographs can be found in the Kautz Family YMCA Archives photo collection.
World War I photo albums and scrapbooks are separately cataloged in the Armed Services Scrapbooks and Photo Albums.
OTHER FINDING AIDS
See the summary inventory for the YMCA Armed Services Records for information on other Armed Services records in the Kautz Family YMCA Archives. >> Go to the summary inventory
INDEX TERMS
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Topics:
Prisoners of War.; Soldiers -- Recreation.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Personal narratives.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Prisoners and prisons.; World War, 1914-1918 -- War work -- Young Men's Christian Associations.
Places:
Mexican-American Border Region.; United States -- Armed Forces -- Military life -- Newspapers.; United States -- Armed Forces -- Religious life.; United States -- Armed Forces -- Songs and music.
Organizations:
American Library Association.; National Board of the Young Men's Christian Associations. Army and Navy Dept.; National Board of the Young Men's Christian Associations. Armed Services Dept.; National Jewish Welfare Board.; National War Work Council, Y.M.C.A. of the United States.; Salvation Army.; United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; United War Work Campaign, Inc.; Young Men's Christian Associations of North America. International Committee. Army and Navy Dept.